Guide to the Wendell Holmes Stephenson Papers, 1820-1968
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Journal of Southern History: Correspondence, 1854-1943, bulk, 1928-1943
  - Hudson, Palmer, 1942 (Box 62)
  - Huguenot Society of South Carolina, 1935-1941, undated (Box 62)
  - Hulett, Oits C., 1939-1940 (Box 62)
  - Hyneman, Charles S., 1939-1941, undated (Box 62)
  - Ia-Iv, 1933-1941 (Box 62)
  - Ideson, Julia, 1937-1941 (Box 62)
  - Ja-Ju, 1934-1942 (Box 62)
  - Jack, Theodore H., 1939-1942 (Box 62)
  - Jocher, Katherine, 1936 (Box 62)
  - Jones, John Paul, Jr., 1940-1941 (Box 62)
  - Jordon, Philip D., 1935-1941 (Box 62)
  - Jordon, Wyemouth T., 1939-1942, undated (Box 62)
  - Josephson, Bertha E., 1936-1941 (Box 62)
  - Journal of Southern History, News Section, 1940-1942, undated (Box 62)
  - Ka-Ku, 1934-1943 (Box 63)
  - Karlin, J. Alexander, 1939-1942 (Box 63)
  - Kearny, Thomas, 1937-1939, undated (Box 63)
  - Kellar, Herbert A., 1935-1941, undated, (3 folders) (Box 63)
  - Kelly, A. R., 1941 (Box 63)
  - Kendrick, Benjamin B., 1935-1942 (Box 63)
  - Kibler, Lillian, 1937-1940, undated (Box 63)
  - Klingbert, Frank J., 1938-1941, undated (Box 63)
  - Knapp, Charles M., 1934-1936 (Box 63)
  - Knott, Gertrude, 1935-1936, undated (Box 63)
  - Koontz, Louis K., 1938-1941, undated (Box 63)
  - Lac-Ly, 1934-1941, (3 folders) (Box 63)
  - Lafuze, G. Leighton, 1937-1941 (Box 64)
  - Landers, Emmett M., 1935-1938 (Box 64)
  - Landon, Fred, 1937-1939 (Box 64)
  - Lanning, John Tate, 1935-1942 (Box 64)
  - Lathrop, Barnes F., 1935-1940 (Box 64)
  - Lefler, Hugh T., 1936-1942 (Box 64)
  - Leland, Edward A., Jr., 1937-1938 (Box 64)
  - Little, Brown and Co., 1935-1940 (Box 64)
  - Litton, Gaston L., 1939-1941 (Box 64)
  - Lonn, Ella, 1935-1942 (Box 64)
  - Louisiana State University Press, 1936-1941, undated (Box 64)
  - Luthin, Reinhard H., 1935-1942 (Box 64)
  - Lynch, William O., 1934-1942 (Box 64)
  - Lyon, E. Wilson, 1935-1941 (Box 64)
  - Ma-Mo, 1934-1943, undated, (2 folders) (Box 64)
  - Martin, Bessie, 1935 (Box 64)
  - Masterson, W. H., 1939 (Box 64)
  - Mayflower Hotel, 1939-1941, undated (Box 64)
  - Mays, Elizabeth, 1936-1937 (Box 64)
  - McAnear, Beverly, 1941-1942, undated (Box 64)
  - McCain, William D., 1938-1942, undated (Box 64)
  - McDonald, Hunter, 1935-1937 (Box 64)
  - McDonald, Kenneth M., 1936 (Box 64)
  - McGinty, G. W., 1935-1942, undated (Box 64)
  - McLemore, R. A., 1935-1941 (Box 64)
  - Macmillan Co., 1934-1941, undated (Box 64)
  - McMurtrie, Douglas C., 1937-1940, undated (Box 64)
  - Mabry, W. A., 1934-1938, undated (Box 64)
  - Malin, James C., 1938-1942, undated (Box 64)
  - Malone, Dumas, Dictionary of American Biography, 1934-1935 (Box 64)
  - Maltby, Lucian G., 1938, undated (Box 64)
  - Manuscript Committee, American Historical Assoc., 1940, undated (Box 65)
  - Marchman, Watt, 1936-1942, undated (Box 65)
  - Marquette, C. H., 1939-1942, undated (Box 65)
  - Martin, T. P., 1935-1941 (Box 65)
  - Masters' Theses, Louisiana State University, 1932-1934, undated (Box 65)
  - Matthews, John C., 1936-1937 (Box 65)
  - Mayo, Bernard, 1937-1942 (Box 65)
  - Meade, Robert D., 1936-1941, undated (Box 65)
  - Mendenhall, Marjorie, 1936-1938 (Box 65)
  - Meriwether, R. L., 1936-1941, undated (Box 65)
  - Mier, Ruth E., 1938-1939 (Box 65)
  - Miles, Guy, 1941-1942 (Box 65)
  - Milner, Clyde A., 1939-1940 (Box 65)
  - Milton, George Fort, 1931-1936, undated (Box 65)
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Association, 1929-1941 (Box 65)
  - Mitchell, George, 1937-1940 (Box 65)
  - Moffitt, James W., 1936-1943 (Box 65)
  - Moger, Allan W., 1937-1941, undated (Box 65)
  - Monaghan, J., 1940 (Box 65)
  - Montgomery, Horace, 1941-1942, undated (Box 65)
  - Moody, V. Alton, 1938-1940 (Box 65)
  - Moore, A. B., 1934-1942, undated (Box 65)
  - Moore, Glover, 1937-1942 (Box 66)
  - Moore, Ike, 1937-1940 (Box 66)
  - Moore, Powell, 1936-1938, undated (Box 66)
  - Moore-Cottrell Subscription Agencies, Inc., 1935-1941 (Box 66)
  - Morse, Jarvis M., 1935-1940, undated (Box 66)
  - Morton, Richard Lee, 1935-1942 (Box 66)
  - Mowry, George E., 1938-1940, undated (Box 66)
  - Mullett, Charles F., 1940-1942 (Box 66)
  - Mutual Subscription Agency, 1937-1941, undated (Box 66)
  - Na-Nz, 1934-1942 (Box 66)
  - National Archives, 1937-1941 (Box 66)
  - National Policy Committee, 1937 (Box 66)
  - Naylor Press, 1935-1937 (Box 66)
  - Nettels, Curtis, P., 1941-1942 (Box 66)
  - Newsome, A. R., 1935-1941 (Box 66)
  - Newspapers-Literary Editors, 1935 (Box 66)
  - Nixon, H. C., 1935-1942 (Box 66)
  - Norton, Leslie M., 1937-1942, undated (Box 66)
  - Nuermberger, Ruth K., 1935-1939 (Box 66)
  - Ob-Ow, 1935-1943 (Box 66)
  - Osborn, George Coleman, 1935-1942 (Box 66)
  - Overdyke, W. Darrell, 1934-1940 (Box 66)
  - Owsley, Frank L., 1941-1942 (Box 66)
  - Oxford University Press, 1935-1940 (Box 66)
  - Pa-Py, 1934-1942, (3 folders) (Box 67)
  - Padgett, James A., 1936-1939 (Box 67)
  - Parks, Joseph Howard, 1938-1942, undated (Box 67)
  - Patton, James W., 1935-1943, undated, (5 folders) (Box 67)
  - Pearce, Haywood T., 1935-1939 (Box 68)
  - Pennington, Edgar L., 1935-1943 (Box 68)
  - Peterson, Arthur G., 1940-1942 (Box 68)
  - Pipkin, Charles W., 1935-1941 (Box 68)
  - Poage, George R., 1934-1938 (Box 68)
  - Pomfret, John, 1936-1941 (Box 68)
  - Porter, Alexander, 1931-1935, undated (Box 68)
  - Posey, Walter B., 1934-1942 (Box 68)
  - Post Office, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1935-1941 (Box 68)
  - Potter, David M., 1938-1941 (Box 68)
  - Potts, J. E., 1935-1937 (Box 68)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1934-1940 (Box 68)
  - Price, Grady D., 1939-1942 (Box 68)
  - Prichard, Walter, 1935-1941 (Box 68)
  - Princeton University Press, 1941-1942 (Box 68)
  - Q, 1937-1941 (Box 68)
  - Queener, Verton M., 1935-1940 (Box 68)
  - Ra-Rz, 1934-1942, (2 folders) (Box 68)
  - Rainwater, Percy, 1935-1938 (Box 68)
  - Rainwater, Percy, 1939, undated (Box 69)
  - Randall, J. G., 1935-1941 (Box 69)
  - Randolph, Bessie C., 1935 (Box 69)
  - Ray, Florence, 1936 (Box 69)
  - Read, Conyers, 1936-1941 (Box 69)
  - Recommendations--Students, 1935-1940 (Box 69)
  - Reeves, G. C., 1935-1938 (Box 69)
  - Renshaw, Grace, 1936-1941 (Box 69)
  - Resignations, 1941-1942, undated (Box 69)
  - Rice, Harvey, 1940-1941 (Box 69)
  - Richardson, R. N., 1934-1941 (Box 69)
  - Rippy, J. Fred, 1936-1941 (Box 69)
  - Rister, C. C., 1934-1940 (Box 69)
  - Rivers, Ernest, 1937 (Box 69)
  - Robert, Joseph C., 1935-1942, undated (Box 69)
  - Robinson, William M., Jr., 1935-1941, undated (Box 69)
  - Robison, Daniel M., 1936-1942, undated (Box 69)
  - Rorer, Henry S., 1938-1939, undated (Box 69)
  - Russ, William A., Jr., 1935-1941 (Box 69)
  - Russel, Robert R., 1937 (Box 69)
  - Sa-Sy, 1934-1943, (4 folders) (Box 69)
  - Saloutos, Theodore, 1938-1940, undated (Box 70)
  - Sanders, J. B., 1935-1940 (Box 70)
  - Sanger, D. B., 1935-1941 (Box 70)
  - Saville, R. J., 1940, undated (Box 70)
  - Schauinger, Joseph H., 1940-1941, undated (Box 70)
  - Schmidt, Louis B., 1941-1942, undated (Box 70)
  - Schoen, Harold, 1937 (Box 70)
  - Schuyler, R. L., 1940-1941 (Box 70)
  - Scribner's Sons, 1934-1936 (Box 70)
  - Scroggs, William O., 1936-1937 (Box 70)
  - Seal, Albert Garrell, 1935-1939, undated (Box 70)
  - Sellers, J. L., 1935-1940, undated (Box 70)
  - Sensabaugh, Leon F., 1935-1941 (Box 70)
  - Shanks, Henry T., Jr., 1935-1939 (Box 70)
  - Shanks, John H., 1938-1939 (Box 70)
  - Shippee, Lester B., 1937-1941 (Box 70)
  - Shively, Hazel, 1935-1938 (Box 70)
  - Shpall, Leo, 1941-1942, undated (Box 70)
  - Shryock, Richard H., 1934-1941, undated (Box 70)
  - Shugg, Roger W., 1936-1942, undated (Box 70)
  - Simkins, Francis B., 1937-1941, undated (Box 70)
  - Silver, James W., 1934-1942, undated (Box 70)
  - Simms, H. H., 1935-1941, undated (Box 70)
  - Simpson, Albert F., 1940-1941 (Box 70)
  - Sioussat, St. George L., 1936-1940 (Box 70)
  - Sitterson, J. Carlyle, 1936-1941, undated (Box 70)
  - Skipper, O. C., 1935-1942, undated (Box 71)
  - Smith, Culver H., 1935-1941 (Box 71)
  - Smith, Justin H., 1936, undated (Box 71)
  - Smith, James M., 1935-1939 (Box 71)
  - Smith, Willard H., 1940-1942 (Box 71)
  - Social Forces, 1935 (Box 71)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1938-1941, undated (Box 71)
  - The Social Studies, 1934-1935 (Box 71)
  - Society of American Archivists, 1937-1938, undated (Box 71)
  - Sorey, Honor, 1940, undated (Box 71)
  - Southern Historical Association, 1934-1940, undated (Box 71)
  - Southwestern Social Science Association, 1934-1935, undated (Box 71)
  - Special Orders, 1941-1943, undated (Box 71)
  - Spengler, Joseph H., 1935-1937, undated (Box 71)
  - Staples, Thomas S., 1937-1941 (Box 71)
  - Stenberg, Richard R., 1935-1940, undated (Box 71)
  - Stewart, Watt, 1935-1938 (Box 71)
  - Stickles, A. M., 1936-1940 (Box 71)
  - Still, Bayrd, 1940-1942 (Box 71)
  - Stoker, Beatrice, 1939-1940 (Box 71)
  - Stone, Alfred H., 1936-1939 (Box 71)
  - Strong, Charles F., 1935-1940 (Box 71)
  - Subscriptions, 1934-1941, undated, (4 folders) (Box 72)
  - Summers, F. P., 1936-1941 (Box 72)
  - Swearingen, Mack B., 1934-1942, undated (Box 72)
  - Sweet, William W., 1934-1937 (Box 72)
  - Swem, Earl Gregg, 1935-1937 (Box 72)
  - Swint, H. L., 1939-1942 (Box 72)
  - Sydnor, Charles S., 1934-1939 (Box 72)
  - Sydnor, Charles S., 1940-1942, undated (Box 73)
  - T, 1935-1943 (Box 73)
  - Talman, James J., 1938-1939 (Box 73)
  - Taylor, Rosser H., 1936-1942 (Box 73)
  - Teas, Thomas Scattergood: Diary of, 1941 (Box 73)
  - Thomas, A. B., 1935-1942 (Box 73)
  - Thomas, David Y., 1935-1942 (Box 73)
  - Thompson, Holland, 1934-1939, undated (Box 73)
  - Thornton, Harrison John, 1934-1935 (Box 73)
  - Tilley, Nannie M., 1938-1940 (Box 73)
  - Toler, Vera, 1935-1937 (Box 73)
  - Trexler, Harrison A., 1935-1941 (Box 73)
  - U, 1934-1942, undated (Box 73)
  - Ulrich B. Phillips Memorial Publication, 1937-1940, undated (Box 73)
  - University of Minessota Press, 1935-1940 (Box 73)
  - University of North Carolina Press, 1934-1941 (Box 73)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1935-1942 (Box 73)
  - Urban, Stanley, 1939-1941 (Box 73)
  - Usher, Robert J., 1935-1940 (Box 73)
  - V, 1936-1943 (Box 73)
  - Vance, Rupert P., 1936-1940 (Box 73)
  - Vasse, Lionel (William Faulkner Honored), 1950 (Box 73)
  - Venable, Austin L., 1938-1942 (Box 73)
  - Violette, E. M., 1938-1940 (Box 73)
  - Virginia Historical Society, 1935-1942 (Box 73)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review, 1935-1939 (Box 73)
  - Volwiler, A. T., 1938-1941 (Box 73)
  - Wa-Wy, 1935-1942, (3 folders) (Box 73)
  - Walker, Evans and Cogswell Co., 1935-1936 (Box 73)
  - Walker, Casper, 1940-1941 (Box 73)
  - Wallace, D. D., 1935-1942 (Box 73)
  - Watters, Mary, 1935-1936 (Box 73)
  - Wentworth, T. T. Jr., 1937-1938 (Box 74)
  - Wertenbaker, Thomas J., 1937-1942 (Box 74)
  - Wesley, Charles H., 1941-1942 (Box 74)
  - White, Laura A., 1935-1940 (Box 74)
  - Wiley, B. I., 1935-1942, undated (Box 74)
  - Willey, Norman L., 1939 (Box 74)
  - William and Mary Quarterly, 1935-1942, undated (Box 74)
  - Williams, Clanton W., 1937-1941 (Box 74)
  - Williams, Justin, 1935-1936 (Box 74)
  - Wilson, Charles R., 1936-1941, undated (Box 74)
  - Wilson, William A. Jr., 1935-1940, undated (Box 74)
  - Winther, Oscar O., 1941 (Box 74)
  - Wirth, Fremont P., 1936-1938 (Box 74)
  - Wish, Harvey, 1937-1942, undated (Box 74)
  - Wittke, Carl, 1939-1940 (Box 74)
  - Woodfin, Maude H., 1935-1942 (Box 74)
  - Woodward, C. Vann, 1937-1941 (Box 74)
  - Woody, Robert H., 1934-1943, undated, (3 folders) (Box 74)
  - Wright, Gordon, 1939-1941 (Box 74)
  - Wright, Louis B., 1939-1941 (Box 74)
  - Wyman, Walker, 1935-1937 (Box 74)
  - Y-Z, 1934-1942 (Box 74)
  - Yates, Richard E., 1936-1942 (Box 74)
- Journal of Southern History: Subject Files, 1850-1944 (bulk 1934-1944)
  Primarily material relating to historical associations, universities, book reviews and articles on Southern history, and the Journal of Southern History. Arranged alphabetically.
  - American Association for State and Local History, 1941 (Box 75)
  - American Historical Association: Committee on Manuscripts, undated (Box 75)
  - Annals of Congress: Want List, undated (Box 75)
  - Appointments and Resignations, 1942 (Box 75)
  - Book Review Records, 1939-1942, undated, (3 folders) (Box 75)
  - Butler, Richard: Diary, undated (Box 75)
  - Cole, Fred C.: Projects in Southern History, 1941, undated (Box 75)
  - Conference of State and Local Historical Societies, 1937, Dec. 31 (Box 75)
  - Conference on Southern Life and Culture: LSU, 1939, Apr. 17-18 (Box 75)
  - Dictionary of American History Articles, undated (Box 75)
  - Economic History Association, 1940 (Box 75)
  - Edward Douglas White Lectures, 1940 (Box 75)
  - Emory University, 1941 (Box 75)
  - Free Negroes in New Orleans, 1850 (List), undated (Box 75)
  - Hesseltine, W. B.: Propaganda Literature of Confederate Prisons, undated (Box 75)
  - Haydon, Stansbury: Aeronautics in the Union and Confederate Armies, undated (Box 75)
  - Historical Publications and Addresses, undated (Box 75)
  - History 22A, 1938-1940, undated (Box 75)
  - Inventory, 1936-1940, undated (Box 75)
  - Invoices and Requisitions, 1935-1942, undated, (2 folders) (Box 76)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1941 (Box 76)
  - Journal of the First Kentucky Convention: Thomas P. Abernethy, Ed., undated (Box 76)
  - Journal of Southern History:
    - Budget, 1935-1944, undated (Box 76)
    - First copy, 1935 (Box 76)
    - Membership Lists, sample copy, undated (Box 76)
    - Miscellany, 1934-1941, undated (Box 76)
  - Louisiana Historical Society, 1934-1936 (Box 76)
  - Louisiana State University:
    - Archives Department, 1938, undated (Box 76)
    - Diamond Jubilee, 1935-1938 (Box 76)
    - Travel Expense Vouchers, 1935-1940, undated (Box 76)
  - Louisiana State University Budget Committee, 1940-1941, undated (Box 77)
  - Master's Degree Requirements, undated (Box 77)
  - News and Notices:
    - May 1942 issue, 1941-1942, undated (Box 77)
    - Aug., 1942 issue, 1942, undated (Box 77)
  - Newspaper collections, undated (Box 77)
  - Plantation Rules, from Southern Sentinel, 1855 (Box 77)
  - Record of Articles, 1938-1942, undated (Box 77)
  - Requisitions, Supplies and Equipment: Bursar, 1934-1942, undated, (2 folders) (Box 77)
  - Research Activity of Historians In and Concerning the South, undated (Box 77)
  - Santoro, Carl: A Stay-at-Home Voting Plan, undated (Box 77)
  - Southern Historical Association: Membership, 1935, undated (Box 77)
  - Texas and the Southwest Bibliography, 1938 (Box 77)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture: Historical Bibliography, 1934 (Box 77)
  - University of North Carolina Library, undated (Box 77)
- Research and Bibliographical Notes, undated
  Note cards arranged in groups according to persons, topics, and places in Southern and American history from the colonial period into the 20th century.
  - Research and Bibliographical Notes, undated (Box 78)